TULSI SHARMA

Business Development Manager

Experienced and self-motivated sales professional with well-rounded sales management skills & 11 years of Industrial experience. Excellent analytic and decision-making skills which are paramount within a fast-moving business environment. Strength in developing & implementing plan for acquiring new business and generating business from existing accounts. Delivering sales figures and new accounts. I am seen as an expert in my role due to the knowledge drive and enthusiasm I possess.

- 9871210749
- sharma.tulsi1991@gmail.com
- Rohini sector 6, New Delhi 110085

EDUCATION

B.A

Delhi University 2012-2015

MBA

IIBM 2022-2023

SKILLS

- Business Development Management
- Channel, B2B & B2C Sales Management Skills
- Client Relationship Management Skills
- Market Research Key Account Specialist
- Strategic Sales Planning Skills

Experience

Mar 2023 - Present O2O Venturez Pvt Ltd, Delhi/NCR (In-store Radio Services)

Business Development Manager

- 🛮 End to end sales and achieve Growth and hit the sales targets.
- Magnetic Design and implement a strategic business plan that expands company's customer base and ensure it's strong pressure.
- ${\tt f B}$ Build and promote strong, long-lasting customer relationships by partnering with them and understanding their needs.
- $\ensuremath{\mathbb{N}}$ Identify emerging markets and market shifts while being fully aware of new products and status.
- 🛮 Revenue and lead generation through existing and prospect clients.
- 🛮 Travel within the Delhi/NCR for the client meetings to close the deal.

Oct 2021 - Feb 2023

Marg ERP Limited, Wazirpur - Delhi (ERP Billing Software)

Zonal Sales Assistant Manager

- Handling team of sales partners and company ASM of UP Zone.
- Working on weekly and monthly sales closing.
- Monitoring the sales performance of the sales team.
- ☐ Internal coordination with different Departments for their billing, Service, payment related issues
- Identifying opportunities and strategies to increase sales.
- Ensuring that the all partners having stock of software.
- $\hfill \square$ Working on process of travelling expense clearance of marketing team.

Jun 2019 - Oct 2021

Woodver Coatings Pvt Ltd, Peeragarhi, Delhi (Wood Paints)

Sales Coordinator and CRM

- ☐ Worked in SAP software.
- Sending quotations through the software and taking confirmation to convert in sales order and execute the Shipment accordingly.
- ☐ Generating bills against the sales order and making e-way bills accordingly.
- ☐ Working on Google drive for customer complaint resolution process.
- Working on sample arrangements as per customer requirement.
- ☐ Follow up with clients for payment collections via phone calls and e-mails.
- 🛘 Internal coordination with different Departments for their billing, Service,
- payment related issues.
- $\ensuremath{\square}$ Filing and retrieving corporate records, document, and reports

- Customer Service & Procurement
- Innovative Problem Solving
- Interpersonal Communication Skills
- Negotiation
- Digital Marketing Skills
- Sales Closer with Lead Generation Skills

LANGUAGE

English

Hindi

HOBBIES

Public Relations

Self-discipline

Apr 2017 - Jun 2019

Icrotone Pvt Ltd, Peeragarhi - Delhi (Wood Paints)

Sales Coordinator

- ☑ Having good working experience of Google drive/spread sheets.
- 🛮 Follow up with clients for payment collections via phone calls and e-mails.
- $\ \ \, \square$ Direct coordinating with sales executives, dealer and customers of company for their sales related enquiries.
- $\ensuremath{\mathbb{N}}$ Internal coordination with different Departments for their billing, Service, payment related issues.
- 🛮 Working on contractor scheme payment.
- 🛮 Working on sample arrangements as per customer requirement.
- 🛮 Working on process of travelling expense clearance of marketing team.
- 🛮 Preparing financial reports, letters and other documents.
- 🛮 Filing and retrieving corporate records, documents, and reports.

Jul 2012 - Mar 2017

Okaya Power Ltd., Peeragarhi, Delhi

Marketing Sales Support Coordinator

- $\ \square$ 20-30 sales calls per day to esteem and existing clients for generating the sale.
- $\hfill \square$ Sending quotations through the software and taking confirmation to convert in sales order and execute the Shipment.
- $\hfill \square$ Coordination with stock department to arrange delivery of material as per PO to dispatch the material to party without delay.
- Internal coordination with different Departments for their billing, Service, payment related issues.
- ☐ Coordination with client for payment collection, C forms and E-Waybill via phone calls and e-mails.
- Direct coordination with sales executives and client of company via phone calls and e-mails.
- $\hfill \square$ Managing the trade India and India Mart profile of the company and calling for new sale.
- $\hfill \square$ New customer Data mining work via web surfing.
- $\hfill\square$ Working on process of travelling expense clearance of marketing team.